<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://Design-and-Innovation-2023.github.io/Team10B/blog</id>
    <title>Curio Blog</title>
    <updated>2023-07-31T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
    <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://Design-and-Innovation-2023.github.io/Team10B/blog"/>
    <subtitle>Curio Blog</subtitle>
    <icon>https://Design-and-Innovation-2023.github.io/Team10B/img/CurioLogo-71x66.png</icon>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Progress Update (2023-07-31)]]></title>
        <id>https://Design-and-Innovation-2023.github.io/Team10B/blog/2023-07-31-progress-update</id>
        <link href="https://Design-and-Innovation-2023.github.io/Team10B/blog/2023-07-31-progress-update"/>
        <updated>2023-07-31T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today’s Progress:]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="todays-progress">Today’s Progress:<a href="#todays-progress" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Today’s Progress:" title="Direct link to Today’s Progress:">​</a></h2><p><strong>Website Development and Usability Testing:</strong></p><p>We made some modifications on our website after conducting usability testing and incorporating feedback received. The website can be accessed here: <!-- -->[Curio]<!-- -->(<a href="https://design-and-innovation-2023.github.io/Team10B/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://design-and-innovation-2023.github.io/Team10B/</a></p><p><strong>Feedback and Improvements:</strong></p><p>The usability testing, performed by the professor and a student, yielded several constructive comments that allowed us to improve our website’s user experience:</p><ol><li><p><strong>Front page clarity</strong>: Originally, the front page seemed promotional rather than informative. It was also perceived as being too wordy, creating confusion between it being a product page or a blog. We worked on this feedback by streamlining the content and making it more straightforward.</p></li><li><p><strong>GitHub link</strong>: The inclusion of the GitHub link led some users to believe we were promoting an open-source project. We felt that the github link was a useful addition to the website to allow users to find relevant code relating to the curio robot.</p></li><li><p><strong>Project ownership</strong>: It was unclear who was behind the project. We addressed this by adding an about us section on our website.</p></li><li><p><strong>Target audience</strong>: Users were unsure who the robot was designed for.</p></li><li><p><strong>Changes to the robot</strong>: Users were able to identify the changes made to the robot, indicating that our visual presentations were effective.</p></li><li><p><strong>Design journal clarity</strong>: The design journal was missing the process and thinking behind our design decisions. We added the dailies to our website under the blog section to address the issue on the lack of thinking behind our design.</p></li><li><p><strong>Explanation of sketches</strong>: Users wanted to see explanations for our design sketches. The explanations were done on the prototype page.</p></li><li><p><strong>Navigation</strong>: The design of the page didn’t clearly guide users to where they could find the design sketches and ideas. We added a navigation tab at the left side of the design journal page to allow the user to traverse the different pages.)</p></li></ol><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="learning-points">Learning Points<a href="#learning-points" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Learning Points" title="Direct link to Learning Points">​</a></h2><p>We tried our best to address all these points of feedback in the latest iteration of our website. We also better understood the importance of usability testing having experienced it. It allowed us to better understand what the user goes through when browsing our website and their thoughts and actions when interacting with the website. This helps us understand the pain points of our website and make adjustments to enhance the user experience when browsing the website. We will continue to monitor user feedback and make further enhancements as necessary. Usability testing proved to be an invaluable tool in our design process, helping us create a website that is not only user-friendly but also effectively communicates our project’s essence and progress.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Team 10B</name>
        </author>
        <category label="progress-update" term="progress-update"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Progress Update (2023-07-28)]]></title>
        <id>https://Design-and-Innovation-2023.github.io/Team10B/blog/2023-07-28-progress-update</id>
        <link href="https://Design-and-Innovation-2023.github.io/Team10B/blog/2023-07-28-progress-update"/>
        <updated>2023-07-28T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today’s Progress:]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="todays-progress">Today’s Progress:<a href="#todays-progress" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Today’s Progress:" title="Direct link to Today’s Progress:">​</a></h2><p><strong>Usability Testing Lesson:</strong></p><p>Today, we had a lesson on usability testing. The session emphasized the importance of ensuring our designs and prototypes are both effective and user-friendly. The key takeaways are:</p><ul><li>Usability testing allows us to identify potential issues and areas of confusion in a design before it becomes a finalized product.</li><li>The process involves asking the intended users of a product to perform certain tasks under observation. This enables us to see where they might encounter problems or feel confused.</li><li>Collecting data from a diverse user base is crucial as different individuals might interact with the product differently.</li><li>The feedback collected from usability testing is a vital resource that can guide us in refining and enhancing our design.</li></ul><p><strong>Instruction Creation Activity:</strong></p><p>We also conducted an activity that involved creating instructions to guide a user in building a specific object. In our case, we decided to write steps to create a paper plane. We unexpectedly found that it was difficult to write steps to create the paper plane as it had to be specific enough for the user to recreate the plane and simple enough that the steps were not too complex and prevent the user from following or understanding the steps. This exercise highlighted the need for clear and concise instructions that users of varying ages and abilities can follow easily.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="learning-points">Learning points<a href="#learning-points" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Learning points" title="Direct link to Learning points">​</a></h2><ul><li>Understanding your audience: Knowing whether we are testing on a teenager or an older individual, for instance, is crucial, as it might influence how the instructions are designed and delivered.</li><li>Time taken to learn: Monitoring the time it takes for a user to learn how to use or build the prototype can provide valuable insights into the intuitiveness and ease-of-use of our designs.</li><li>we also learnt the importance of giving the right tasks for the testing such as making it actionable, realistic, specific, in order to obtain the most information from the user, such as their thought process when navigating our website.</li></ul>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Team 10B</name>
        </author>
        <category label="progress-update" term="progress-update"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Weekly Pitch 2 Feedback (2023-07-28)]]></title>
        <id>https://Design-and-Innovation-2023.github.io/Team10B/blog/2023-07-28-weekly-pitch-2-feedback</id>
        <link href="https://Design-and-Innovation-2023.github.io/Team10B/blog/2023-07-28-weekly-pitch-2-feedback"/>
        <updated>2023-07-28T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[IMAGE ALT TEXT HERE]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zYYJXYxaqTI" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><img loading="lazy" src="https://img.youtube.com/vi/zYYJXYxaqTI/0.jpg" alt="IMAGE ALT TEXT HERE" class="img_ev3q"></a></p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="teaching-assistant-claretb">Teaching Assistant (claretb)<a href="#teaching-assistant-claretb" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Teaching Assistant (claretb)" title="Direct link to Teaching Assistant (claretb)">​</a></h2><p>Except the speed of video, everything seems fine for video style.</p><p>Clients gave some feedback on last week’s video, but it seems there were <strong>no meeting and questions from the team this week to receive more</strong>. I was expecting to see <strong>more feedbacks and learnings from users</strong>.</p><p>I <strong>can’t understand the idea behind prototype 2</strong>. How people create their own designs? If they create their own, which issue is solved by this prototype? I think it is already Smartibot and do you have enough materials and instructions like Smartibot?</p><p>Attachment idea sounds good, but we want to see <strong>something tested at this stage</strong>. There are some possibilities about its usage, but did you created attachments and tested them with the robot? How about your partners? Did they hear about it in a meeting?</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="professor-jgrizou">Professor (jgrizou)<a href="#professor-jgrizou" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Professor (jgrizou)" title="Direct link to Professor (jgrizou)">​</a></h2><p>Felt at the edge of the speed conformable to follow what you say. It was a big hard to follow.</p><p><strong>Learned from user</strong></p><p>It felt more like a defense of your choices than an acknowledgement of what was learned. Can you see why I am saying this and the difference between the two?</p><p><strong>Learned from prototype</strong></p><p><strong>Why would lower center of gravity = more speed?</strong> Just curious on a physics basis I am not sure it make sense or what you are trying to get to.</p><p>Prototype 3 felt interesting with the hole on the top of the head to be slided in</p><p><strong>Feedback</strong></p><p>I understand you picked the angle of smartibot mixed with Curio but I am not sure <strong>how feasible what you propose</strong> would be for another person to build.</p><p><strong>What would be a good outcome</strong> for your project? Do you plan to offer the plans of the robot on your website? Maybe a tutorial on how to build it?</p><p>Overall, <strong>I don’t think you met with your client enough :slight_smile:</strong> , there is lot we could have discussed on a day to day basis.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Team 10B</name>
        </author>
        <category label="weekly-pitch" term="weekly-pitch"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Weekly Pitch 2 (2023-07-28)]]></title>
        <id>https://Design-and-Innovation-2023.github.io/Team10B/blog/2023-07-28-weekly-pitch-2</id>
        <link href="https://Design-and-Innovation-2023.github.io/Team10B/blog/2023-07-28-weekly-pitch-2"/>
        <updated>2023-07-28T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[IMAGE ALT TEXT HERE]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zYYJXYxaqTI" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><img loading="lazy" src="https://img.youtube.com/vi/zYYJXYxaqTI/0.jpg" alt="IMAGE ALT TEXT HERE" class="img_ev3q"></a></p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Team 10B</name>
        </author>
        <category label="weekly-pitch" term="weekly-pitch"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Designer Engagement (2023-07-27)]]></title>
        <id>https://Design-and-Innovation-2023.github.io/Team10B/blog/2023-07-27-designer-engagement</id>
        <link href="https://Design-and-Innovation-2023.github.io/Team10B/blog/2023-07-27-designer-engagement"/>
        <updated>2023-07-27T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Designer Sharing]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="designer-sharing">Designer Sharing<a href="#designer-sharing" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Designer Sharing" title="Direct link to Designer Sharing">​</a></h2><ol><li><p>Stepper motor is the most cost efficient to get the result he wants since precision is the goal</p></li><li><p>Constraints : being able to tilt the robot in various angles</p></li><li><p>A lot of the stuff being done is still experimental</p></li><li><p>Would be beneficial if parts are easily assembled and detachable, it takes a while to assemble the entire robot.</p></li><li><p>Trying to keep the material cost down to something sensible for example servo motors with the electronic magnet are not practical as they cost 2/3 of the entire cost making sure the wheels and the back wheel are always in stock. trying to keep the material used simple, might consider implementing 3d printing , consider using plastic for the wheel.</p></li><li><p>Another weak point would be the phone stand. (Very floppy)</p></li><li><p>keep it to a reasonably small amount of parts</p></li><li><p>It is nice to have modularity as most universities are able to 3d print it</p></li><li><p>Curio does have a control board and it is not possible to get the user to make a new control board from scratch, so focus of robot main constraints are the hardware(specifically motor)</p></li></ol><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="designer-feedback-for-team-10a-prototypes">Designer Feedback for team 10A prototypes<a href="#designer-feedback-for-team-10a-prototypes" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Designer Feedback for team 10A prototypes" title="Direct link to Designer Feedback for team 10A prototypes">​</a></h2><ol><li><p>Appreciates the rotation of the 2nd prototype as that facing.so his consideration but advise to ensure the wheels are rotatable in the direction that the camera is facing</p></li><li><p>Reinstate to have easier alternative to tilt the angle of the phone which the team plans to overcome using servo motors to automate angle positioning of the phone</p></li><li><p>When using 3 wheels, need a steering wheel(ball bearing)</p></li></ol><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="designer-feedback-for-team-10b-prototypes">Designer Feedback for team 10B prototypes<a href="#designer-feedback-for-team-10b-prototypes" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Designer Feedback for team 10B prototypes" title="Direct link to Designer Feedback for team 10B prototypes">​</a></h2><ol><li><p>Could consider using a stepper motor rather than DC(smartibot) to aid with the precision.</p></li><li><p>He likes the versality aspect of the design and having the students to assemble to their liking rather than sending an assembled bot which might be damaged in transit.</p></li><li><p>He likes the clamp design and does not have a use case when designing curio, we should think about our use case and work towards it</p></li><li><p>Initially he did not have a use case so the advice was to have a use case to work on the problems, e.g., if speed is something we are working on then focus on that direction such as point 2</p></li></ol>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Team 10B</name>
        </author>
        <category label="designer-engagement" term="designer-engagement"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Progress Update (2023-07-27)]]></title>
        <id>https://Design-and-Innovation-2023.github.io/Team10B/blog/2023-07-27-progress-update</id>
        <link href="https://Design-and-Innovation-2023.github.io/Team10B/blog/2023-07-27-progress-update"/>
        <updated>2023-07-27T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today’s Progress:]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="todays-progress">Today’s Progress:<a href="#todays-progress" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Today’s Progress:" title="Direct link to Today’s Progress:">​</a></h2><p><strong>Designer Engagement Session:</strong>
Today, we had an enriching conversation with the designer of the Curio robot. We discussed various design aspects and gathered valuable insights to steer our prototyping process. Here’s a summary of the key points shared:</p><ul><li>Stepper Motors: The designer emphasized the use of stepper motors as the most cost-efficient option for achieving precision, a key requirement for the Curio robot.</li><li>Constraints: Challenges include enabling the robot to tilt at various angles.</li><li>Experimental Process: The designer acknowledged that a lot of the ongoing work is still experimental.</li><li>Easy Assembly and Detachability: He pointed out that it takes a while to assemble the entire robot, and an easy-to-assemble and detachable design would be beneficial.</li><li>Keeping Material Costs Low: Efforts are made to use cost-effective materials. For example, servo motors with electronic magnets were deemed impractical as they would cost two-thirds of the entire cost. The wheels and back wheel are always kept in stock, and materials used are kept simple, with possibilities of using 3D printing and plastic for wheels.</li><li>Phone Stand: The current phone stand design was identified as a weak point due to its floppiness.</li><li>Modularity: Modularity is preferred as most universities can 3D print the components.</li><li>Hardware Constraints: Curio has a control board which is impossible to have users make from scratch. Thus, the main constraints for the robot are in hardware, specifically the motor.</li></ul><p><strong>Feedback on our Prototype:</strong></p><ul><li>The designer suggested using a stepper motor instead of a DC motor (like in the Smartibot) to aid with precision.</li><li>He praised the versatility of our design, which allows students to assemble the robot as per their preference instead of shipping a fully assembled bot, which might get damaged in transit.</li><li>He was impressed with the clamp design, suggesting we should consider our specific use case and work towards it.</li></ul><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="teaching-assistant-claretb-feedback">Teaching Assistant (claretb) Feedback<a href="#teaching-assistant-claretb-feedback" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Teaching Assistant (claretb) Feedback" title="Direct link to Teaching Assistant (claretb) Feedback">​</a></h2><blockquote><p><strong>Team10B:</strong> We agreed that we need to further refine our design to increase its value in facilitating learning. This includes justifying design choices, such as the addition of a adjustable phone stand at the back of the Smartibot.</p></blockquote><blockquote><p><strong>Claretb:</strong> It’s good idea exactly but can you explain more about how justifying design choices can make the learning better?</p></blockquote><p><strong>Team10B:</strong> Thanks for the question, when we mentioned ‘justifying design choices,’ we meant more about explaining the rationale behind why we’ve chosen to design our robot in a particular way. For example, from the student’s point of view, when they are building and using their Curio robots they are able to understand these design choices gives them insight into how the robot works and why.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="sketches">Sketches<a href="#sketches" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Sketches" title="Direct link to Sketches">​</a></h2><p>We came out with another prototype sketch.</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Sketch" src="/Team10B/assets/images/sketch-cadd40f74fe707a841f0c48d66fa9239.jpeg" width="2048" height="1536" class="img_ev3q"></p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="prototype">Prototype<a href="#prototype" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Prototype" title="Direct link to Prototype">​</a></h2><p>We use cardboard to make the sketch prototype.</p><p><strong>Front:</strong></p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Attachment" src="/Team10B/assets/images/front-prototype-2e331c92659d8230ce2c39818aa73e06.jpeg" width="999" height="750" class="img_ev3q"></p><p><strong>Side:</strong></p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Side" src="/Team10B/assets/images/side-prototype-eb8afcd9e190704c18de787a08ff074a.jpeg" width="2048" height="1536" class="img_ev3q"></p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Team 10B</name>
        </author>
        <category label="progress-update" term="progress-update"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Progress Update (2023-07-26)]]></title>
        <id>https://Design-and-Innovation-2023.github.io/Team10B/blog/2023-07-26-progress-update</id>
        <link href="https://Design-and-Innovation-2023.github.io/Team10B/blog/2023-07-26-progress-update"/>
        <updated>2023-07-26T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today’s Progress:]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="todays-progress">Today’s Progress:<a href="#todays-progress" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Today’s Progress:" title="Direct link to Today’s Progress:">​</a></h2><p><strong>Consultation with the Professor</strong>: We consulted with the professor regarding our current prototype design yesterday. The discussion brought to light several key points to ponder about:</p><ol><li><p>We could replace the front design of the smartibot with a simpler design that was easier to assemble.</p></li><li><p>Battery Pack Integration: Incorporating the Curio robot’s battery pack, which can be recharged using a Type-C cable, was considered a valuable step. This will reduce the need for frequent battery replacements when the robot ran out of battery.</p></li><li><p>We agreed that we need to further refine our design to increase its value in facilitating learning. This includes justifying design choices, such as the addition of a adjustable phone stand at the back of the Smartibot.</p></li></ol><p><strong>Feedback Response</strong>: We received some insightful comments suggesting the creation of an attachable design with various modules. The suggestion to consider using the existing Curio design and create additional attachments was especially interesting. We thought of some ideas in that we could add more holes into the base of the curio robot which allowed for modifications or additional modules to be added to the robot via the holes. This could help encourage students to be more creative with their robot designs.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="teaching-assistant-claretb-feedback">Teaching Assistant (claretb) Feedback<a href="#teaching-assistant-claretb-feedback" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Teaching Assistant (claretb) Feedback" title="Direct link to Teaching Assistant (claretb) Feedback">​</a></h2><blockquote><p>We agreed that we need to further refine our design to increase its value in facilitating learning. This includes justifying design choices, such as the addition of a adjustable phone stand at the back of the Smartibot.</p></blockquote><p>It’s good idea exactly but can you explain more about how justifying design choices can make the learning better?</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Team 10B</name>
        </author>
        <category label="progress-update" term="progress-update"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Progress Update (2023-07-25)]]></title>
        <id>https://Design-and-Innovation-2023.github.io/Team10B/blog/2023-07-25-progress-update</id>
        <link href="https://Design-and-Innovation-2023.github.io/Team10B/blog/2023-07-25-progress-update"/>
        <updated>2023-07-25T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today’s Progress:]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="todays-progress">Today’s Progress:<a href="#todays-progress" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Today’s Progress:" title="Direct link to Today’s Progress:">​</a></h2><p><strong>Integrative Thinking Template</strong>: During our class today, we learnt about the concept of integrative thinking. This problem-solving approach allowed us to explore ways to leverage opposing models to generate innovative solutions. We’ve learned and practiced the step-by-step process, as outlined below:</p><ol><li><p>Identify Two Opposing Models: This involves identifying two contrasting models or solutions based on a problem statement.</p></li><li><p>Build a Pro-Pro Chart: In this step, we learned to identify the advantages of each model, encouraging us to value and leverage the strengths of each.</p></li><li><p>Identify the Tension: We discovered how to highlight the core tension between the models</p></li><li><p>Create a new Choice: With a clear understanding of the tension and the pros of each model, we then innovated a new model that integrates the strengths of both while addressing the tension.</p></li></ol><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="sketch-updates">Sketch Updates<a href="#sketch-updates" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Sketch Updates" title="Direct link to Sketch Updates">​</a></h2><p>Alongside our classroom learnings, we continued to build on our design sketches.</p><p><strong>Top view:</strong></p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Top view" src="/Team10B/assets/images/top-2c662304529c9a7e797b802a37bd5b40.jpeg" width="1600" height="1396" class="img_ev3q"></p><p><strong>Attachments:</strong></p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Attachment" src="/Team10B/assets/images/attachments-692372b9ee7e9b4e77427ca5585297eb.jpeg" width="1034" height="1600" class="img_ev3q"></p><p><strong>Side view:</strong></p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Side" src="/Team10B/assets/images/side-a9751af25582c8497aa33b1a44f47fee.jpeg" width="1600" height="1054" class="img_ev3q"></p><p><strong>Shield:</strong></p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Shield" src="/Team10B/assets/images/shield-9532b5050f42bc7f754e81f527f3dc00.jpeg" width="1600" height="954" class="img_ev3q"></p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="teaching-assistant-claretb-feedback">Teaching Assistant (claretb) Feedback<a href="#teaching-assistant-claretb-feedback" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Teaching Assistant (claretb) Feedback" title="Direct link to Teaching Assistant (claretb) Feedback">​</a></h3><p>Attachments:</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Attachment" src="/Team10B/assets/images/attachments-692372b9ee7e9b4e77427ca5585297eb.jpeg" width="1034" height="1600" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>It really makes sense to create an attachable design with some attachments. In this way the robot can be converted to a race car or a sumo bot or anything you want. One of the most attracting things for me is making some modular thing.</p><p>Even you don’t have to create a robot from scratch. Maybe you can use the current Curio design and create some attachments. Just an idea…</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Team 10B</name>
        </author>
        <category label="progress-update" term="progress-update"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Progress Update (2023-07-24)]]></title>
        <id>https://Design-and-Innovation-2023.github.io/Team10B/blog/2023-07-24-progress-update</id>
        <link href="https://Design-and-Innovation-2023.github.io/Team10B/blog/2023-07-24-progress-update"/>
        <updated>2023-07-24T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today’s Progress:]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="todays-progress">Today’s Progress:<a href="#todays-progress" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Today’s Progress:" title="Direct link to Today’s Progress:">​</a></h2><ul><li><p><strong>Sketches</strong>: Our team worked on creating new design sketches using AutoCAD. The focus of these sketches was to envision a design that is simple to assemble and uses recyclable materials such as cardboard.</p></li><li><p><strong>Weekly Pitch Video Feedback</strong>: We received valuable feedback on our presentation video from both our professor and teaching assistant. Their comments have given us a fresh perspective and actionable insights to improve our design process and future presentations.</p></li></ul><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="our-thoughts-on-the-feedback">Our thoughts on the feedback<a href="#our-thoughts-on-the-feedback" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Our thoughts on the feedback" title="Direct link to Our thoughts on the feedback">​</a></h2><p>Overall we felt that our project was on the right track as the our goals and the scope of the project align with what the professor had in mind. We were also able to gain insight into what aspect of the project we should focus on such as the designs and analyses on Curio as well as the specific parts of the Curio robot that can be improved on in terms of sustainability. The professor also pointed out the fact of the likelihood of the robot being damaged which was something that we considered as group and felt that one possible solution was including a “base plate” sort of design where the user could replace the damaged part by cutting out an outline on a piece of cardboard on the base plate. We also noted that we should include what we learnt from the prototypes and pick out certain features or points that can be incorporated into our final design such as the front and back of the smartibot. We gained valuable feedback on the video as a whole and will tweak the future pitch videos to sound less sped up, include our learning and the designs and analyses on Curio.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="autocad-sketches">AutoCAD Sketches<a href="#autocad-sketches" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to AutoCAD Sketches" title="Direct link to AutoCAD Sketches">​</a></h2><p>Front view:</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Front view" src="/Team10B/assets/images/front-0387b872c049ed83fc7238b99b819e1d.jpeg" width="398" height="352" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>Back view:</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Back view" src="/Team10B/assets/images/back-64e3c74ae9373b16b7da2c7b5a967fa1.jpeg" width="543" height="474" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>Side view:</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Side view" src="/Team10B/assets/images/side-93b5bb0867a0ded7a80f373dde4af129.jpeg" width="881" height="365" class="img_ev3q"></p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Team 10B</name>
        </author>
        <category label="progress-update" term="progress-update"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Weekly Pitch 1 Feedback (2023-07-24)]]></title>
        <id>https://Design-and-Innovation-2023.github.io/Team10B/blog/2023-07-24-weekly-pitch-1-feedback</id>
        <link href="https://Design-and-Innovation-2023.github.io/Team10B/blog/2023-07-24-weekly-pitch-1-feedback"/>
        <updated>2023-07-24T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[IMAGE ALT TEXT HERE]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Oz5KXsxkr6E" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><img loading="lazy" src="https://img.youtube.com/vi/Oz5KXsxkr6E/0.jpg" alt="IMAGE ALT TEXT HERE" class="img_ev3q"></a></p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="teaching-assistant-claretb">Teaching Assistant (claretb)<a href="#teaching-assistant-claretb" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Teaching Assistant (claretb)" title="Direct link to Teaching Assistant (claretb)">​</a></h2><p>I liked how in your video, you <strong>expressed your initial thoughts</strong> about the design and then, with the <strong>feedback</strong> from your partner, managed to <strong>define an MVP</strong> for yourselves. This way, you successfully created a <strong>clear goal statement</strong> and sharpened your objectives.</p><p>While reviewing your daily logs, the example of the prototype applied on Curio caught my attention, and I was <strong>hoping to see that sketch</strong> in the video as well. The explanations and the identified problems that could be addressed with this prototype were well expressed. Instead of focusing on Smartibot in the video, it would have been <strong>more effective to highlight and discuss the changes that could be made on Curio</strong>.</p><p>As a team, I can advise you to focus on <strong>creating designs and presenting analyses on Curio</strong>. This way, you can receive feedback more easily from partners and also evaluate your own prototypes to gain insights. If you can also mention the learnings you gained from the prototype next time, I’m sure we will make even more progress.</p><p>P.S. I had a lot of fun with the design of your presentation, the robot figures around it were very intriguing :slight_smile:</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="professor-jgrizou">Professor (jgrizou)<a href="#professor-jgrizou" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Professor (jgrizou)" title="Direct link to Professor (jgrizou)">​</a></h2><p>Video sounds sped up. Please do this with caution, the <strong>video is bordeline too fast</strong> to follow.</p><p><strong>Learned from user</strong></p><p>I am glad we managed to re-align on the scope of this project, I think you now have a good picture of what the goals are.</p><p><strong>How likely do you think it is that a robot get damaged?</strong></p><p>I like the sustainable angle, but was not sure on <strong>which specific parts</strong> do you think we can improve upon?</p><p>Learned from prototype</p><p>I am <strong>not sure about what you learned from the Smartibot</strong> at this stage. Am I right to say that the video say that the Smartibot has a clear front and back because of the face on the robot? <strong>Did you learn anything else from it?</strong></p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Team 10B</name>
        </author>
        <category label="weekly-pitch" term="weekly-pitch"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Progress Update (2023-07-21)]]></title>
        <id>https://Design-and-Innovation-2023.github.io/Team10B/blog/2023-07-21-progress-update</id>
        <link href="https://Design-and-Innovation-2023.github.io/Team10B/blog/2023-07-21-progress-update"/>
        <updated>2023-07-21T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today’s Progress:]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="todays-progress">Today’s Progress:<a href="#todays-progress" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Today’s Progress:" title="Direct link to Today’s Progress:">​</a></h2><p><strong>Clarifying Deliverables</strong>: Today, we had a productive discussion with our professor to gain clarity on the project deliverables. The conversation allowed us to understand the project’s expectations better and what is actually required of the team.</p><p><strong>Simplified Assembly</strong>: The professor stressed the importance of ensuring our final product is easy to assemble, similar to an ‘out-of-the-box’ concept. He also highlighted the comparisons between the curio and smartibot design features and how each design had its own advantages and disadvantages and finding a middle ground between the two designs would be ideal.</p><p><strong>Iterative Design</strong>: We also established that while our final product can be one finalized design, it is crucial to document and demonstrate the design iterations that lead to the final product. This will showcase our design journey and the considerations that shaped the final product.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="prototyping-session">Prototyping Session:<a href="#prototyping-session" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Prototyping Session:" title="Direct link to Prototyping Session:">​</a></h2><p>Our class today was dedicated to understanding more about prototyping methodologies. We gained insights into choosing a prototyping method suitable for our project as well as clearing up any prior misconceptions we had about prototyping. It also helped us learn more about the logic and steps to prototyping that we may not have considered going into the class.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="reflections-and-learnings">Reflections and Learnings:<a href="#reflections-and-learnings" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Reflections and Learnings:" title="Direct link to Reflections and Learnings:">​</a></h2><p>Overall, the professor’s advice has given us a clearer direction on how to approach the design process. We understood the importance of simplicity and ease of assembly in our design, which will guide our prototyping phase. Learning about various prototyping methodologies has also given us a toolbox of techniques we can choose from, depending on the specific needs of each design iteration.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="smartibot">Smartibot<a href="#smartibot" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Smartibot" title="Direct link to Smartibot">​</a></h2><p>We sketched this out to find out more about how we can incorporate certain design features of the smartibot into our prototype.</p><p>Front view of the smartibot:</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Front view" src="/Team10B/assets/images/smartibot-front-192e5fb9efa2aee4c1e29dfd66d13a0b.jpeg" width="1713" height="1803" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>Back view of the smartibot:</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Back view" src="/Team10B/assets/images/smartibot-back-ae3a63635a26bbe6383115d66b5255d0.jpeg" width="2013" height="1921" class="img_ev3q"></p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="images-of-sketches">Images of Sketches:<a href="#images-of-sketches" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Images of Sketches:" title="Direct link to Images of Sketches:">​</a></h2><p>We have sketched some preliminary ideas.</p><p><strong>Initial Idea 1:</strong></p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="idea 1" src="/Team10B/assets/images/idea1-7efbe9c03c15501db3b52606f2e7fff6.jpg" width="1464" height="1612" class="img_ev3q"></p><p><strong>Initial Idea 2:</strong></p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="idea 2" src="/Team10B/assets/images/idea2-764f0f79859fb368eb3be3b1d3fb71f7.jpg" width="1536" height="2048" class="img_ev3q"></p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Team 10B</name>
        </author>
        <category label="progress-update" term="progress-update"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Progress Update (2023-07-20)]]></title>
        <id>https://Design-and-Innovation-2023.github.io/Team10B/blog/2023-07-20-progress-update</id>
        <link href="https://Design-and-Innovation-2023.github.io/Team10B/blog/2023-07-20-progress-update"/>
        <updated>2023-07-20T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today’s Progress:]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="todays-progress">Today’s Progress:<a href="#todays-progress" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Today’s Progress:" title="Direct link to Today’s Progress:">​</a></h2><ul><li><p>Initiated discussions on design iterations for the Curio robot. The primary aim was to add value while still keeping the design affordable and accessible.</p></li><li><p>We strategized and came up with a number of design implementations, aiming to optimize the robot’s functionality and user interaction:</p><ul><li>Face + Speed: A base design using the base features of the smartibot to address the issue with identifying the front of the robot and the speed of the robot</li><li>Smartibot with Curio: Explored the feasibility of integrating Smartibot into Curio. This aims to enhance the design by enabling quicker and more effective design explorations.</li><li>Teapot Design with Phone: Explored the potential of implementing the ‘teapot’ design of the smartibot kit while including a dedicated spot for the user’s phone. This would improve user interaction and extend the capabilities of the robot by leveraging the phone’s sensors.</li><li>Battle Bots: Brainstormed ideas for a ‘Battle Bots’ feature that enables users to add components to the base of the robot using simple household materials.</li><li>Base Plate with Face + Attachments that can Self-Make (Tentative): Contemplated on an innovative base plate design with a ‘face’ and the ability to replace certain components of the robot if faulty using simple household materials given a base plate.</li><li>Challenges: Identifying the balance between innovative design and cost-effectiveness</li></ul></li></ul><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="upcoming-priorities">Upcoming Priorities:<a href="#upcoming-priorities" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Upcoming Priorities:" title="Direct link to Upcoming Priorities:">​</a></h2><ul><li>Start sketching out designs based on the ideas that were generated during the meeting.</li><li>Establishing concrete goals and deadlines for each design iteration.</li></ul>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Team 10B</name>
        </author>
        <category label="progress-update" term="progress-update"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Weekly Pitch 1 (2023-07-20)]]></title>
        <id>https://Design-and-Innovation-2023.github.io/Team10B/blog/2023-07-20-weekly-pitch-1</id>
        <link href="https://Design-and-Innovation-2023.github.io/Team10B/blog/2023-07-20-weekly-pitch-1"/>
        <updated>2023-07-20T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[IMAGE ALT TEXT HERE]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Oz5KXsxkr6E" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><img loading="lazy" src="https://img.youtube.com/vi/Oz5KXsxkr6E/0.jpg" alt="IMAGE ALT TEXT HERE" class="img_ev3q"></a></p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Team 10B</name>
        </author>
        <category label="weekly-pitch" term="weekly-pitch"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Progress Update (2023-07-19)]]></title>
        <id>https://Design-and-Innovation-2023.github.io/Team10B/blog/2023-07-19-progress-update</id>
        <link href="https://Design-and-Innovation-2023.github.io/Team10B/blog/2023-07-19-progress-update"/>
        <updated>2023-07-19T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today’s Progress]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="todays-progress">Today’s Progress<a href="#todays-progress" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Today’s Progress" title="Direct link to Today’s Progress">​</a></h2><ol><li>Split tasks among the team members to maximize efficiency and progress</li><li>Made plans for the prototyping of the curio robot including the initial designs and additional components that can be added to the robot</li><li>Set goals and deadlines to meet in the coming week</li><li>Made arrangements to meet and work on the prototype and project deliverables in the coming days</li></ol>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Team 10B</name>
        </author>
        <category label="progress-update" term="progress-update"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Progress Update (2023-07-18)]]></title>
        <id>https://Design-and-Innovation-2023.github.io/Team10B/blog/2023-07-18-progress-update</id>
        <link href="https://Design-and-Innovation-2023.github.io/Team10B/blog/2023-07-18-progress-update"/>
        <updated>2023-07-18T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Customer Questions]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="customer-questions">Customer Questions<a href="#customer-questions" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Customer Questions" title="Direct link to Customer Questions">​</a></h2><ol><li>Who are the target audience</li><li>What are the limitations of the current design, more specific about the speed(functional and non functional requirements)</li><li>What are the limitations of the hardware aspect</li><li>What are the limitations of the aesthetic aspect </li><li>Are the stakeholders of the company aiming for sustainability by using recyclable items</li><li>If a part of the robot is spoilt, can it be easily replace or do we have to change the entire robot</li><li>What is the current lifespan of the product (durability)</li><li>How is it being charged or is it operated by battery lifespan</li><li>What are the type of mobile or devices that can be used on the robot</li></ol>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Team 10B</name>
        </author>
        <category label="progress-update" term="progress-update"/>
    </entry>
</feed>